Guide to the Robert Ward Papers, 1910-2012 and undated RL.01344
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Music by Others, 1910-2007 and undated; 7
  Music by Others includes a variety of scores and recordings by other composers included in Robert Ward's papers. Majority of items are recordings rather than scores. Recording titles are taken from the media objects themselves. Media include audiocassettes, compact discs, digital audio tapes, LPs, reels, umatic tapes, and VHS tapes. Composers include Hugh Aitken, Samuel Barber, Belá Bartók, Leslie Bassett, William Bergsma, Leonard Bernstein, David Brackett, Margaret Brouwer, Christopher Coleman, Gaetano Donizetti, Scott Eyerely, Ernesto Ferreri, Daniel Foley, Kenneth Frazelle, Barbara Gallagher, Gordon Goodwin, Paul Hindemith, Charles Ives, Hunter Johnson, Aaron Jay Kernis, James Legg, Joseph Leniado-Chira, Scott Lindroth, Henry Mollicone, Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, Russell Peck, Sergei Prokofiev, Sergei Rachmaninoff, J. Mark Scearce, Jack Stamp, Stella Sung, Toru Takemitsu, Giuseppe Verdi, Richard Wargo, Donald Waxman, Ralph Vaughan Williams, and Yehudi Wyner. Arranged alphabetically by composer last name. Several recordings without a listed composer are arranged alphbetically my recording title at the end of the series.
  - Rosa de Fuego, Rhapsody for Piano by Hugh Aitken, undated (Box 85)
  - Symphony of Songs by Jacob Avshalomov, Portland Youth Philharmonic, 26 February 1994 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0227)
  - Vanessa, Part I, by Samuel Barber, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0048)
  - Vanessa, Part II, by Samuel Barber, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0049)
  - Sonatine by Béla Bartók, 1919 (Box 85)
  - Concerto for Orchestra, From a Source Evoling by Leslie Bassett, 0 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0237)
  - Music of William Bergsma, tape 1, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0273)
  - Music of William Bergsma, tape 2, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0274)
  - Music of William Bergsma, tape 3, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0275)
  - Music of William Bergsma, tape 5, undated (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0276)
  - Music of William Bergsma, tape 6, undated (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0277)
  - Candide by Leonard Bernstein, New York City Opera, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0070)
  - Cradle will Rock by Marc Blitzstein, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0063)
  - Music by Andrei Bondarenko, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0264)
  - Dylan Thomas Songs by David Brackett, 19 March 1995 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0229)
  - Music of Walter Braxton, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0270)
  - Light by Margaret Brouwer, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0263)
  - Fantasy for Guitar by David Brackett, undated (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0278)
  - Musique Noire by David Brackett, 1996 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0241)
  - America's Going to the Dickens! by Christopher Coleman, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0245)
  - Music of Carson O. Cooman, 2005 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0103)
  - Music for Horn and Organ by Archangelo Corelli, Henry Purcell, Randall Faust, Gardner Read, undated (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0289)
  - Préludes by Claude Debussy, 1910 (Box 85)
  - Piano works of David Diamond, Piano Sonata by Hunter Johnson, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0255)
  - The House of Seven Gables by Scott Eyerly, 1991 (Box 82)
  - The House of Seven Gables by Scott Eyerly, 23 September 1993 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0246)
  - Blake Songs by Ernesto Ferreri, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0230)
  - Songs of Innocence and of Experience by Ernesto Ferreri, 1995 (Box 82)
  - Young Gil Blas by Ernesto Ferreri, 1993 (Box 82)
    Includes some correspondence with Robert Ward
  - Young Gil Blas by Ernesto Ferreri, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0243)
  - Ernesto Ferrari various works, 1994 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0252)
  - Cenerentola (Cinderella) by Jacopo Ferretti, La Scala, Glyndbourne, undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0073)
  - Cold Sassy Tree by Carlisle Floyd, Houston Grand Opera, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0051)
  - Willie Stark by Carlisle Floyd, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0057)
  - Hommage à Rousseau by Daniel Foley, March 2000 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0235)
  - Music of Ron Ford, undated (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0279)
  - Fantasies for piano by Kenneth Frazelle, 11 February 1980 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0267)
  - Piano Quintet by Kenneth Frazelle, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0232)
  - Piano Trio by Kenneth Frazelle, 2010 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0104)
  - Sonata for Cello and Piano by Kenneth Frazelle, undated (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0281)
  - Untitled recording by Kenneth Frazelle, 2010 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0105)
  - Breath of Life by J. Todd Frazier, 2006-2007 (Box 82)
  - Music by James Funkhouser, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0272)
  - Flute Sonata by Barbara Gallagher, 6 June 2004 (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0283)
  - St. Brigid Songs by Barbara Gallagher, 2010 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0106)
  - H.M.S. Pinafore, The Mikado by W.S. Gilbert and Arthur Sullivan, undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0072)
  - Jungle City by David Good, 1986 (Box 82)
  - Wedding Day by David Good, 1986 (Box 82)
  - Camerata Quintet by Gordon Goodwin, undated (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0294)
  - Camerata Quintet by Gordon Goodwin, undated (Box 82)
  - Howard Hanson V and Finale II; La Mer by Claude Debussy, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0240)
  - Heaven Haven, Janice Harsanyi in concert, 1974 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0154)
  - Fifth Quartet by Paul Hindemith, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0259)
  - Summer and Smoke by Lee Hoiby, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0042)
  - Nine Songs by Charles Ives, 1977 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0008)
  - Symphony No. 1 by Charles Ives, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0257)
  - Letter to the World by Hunter Johnson, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0261)
  - Too Hot Toccata by Aaron Jay Kernis, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0248)
  - Symphony in Waves, String Quartet (musica celestis) by Aaron Jay Kernis, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0249)
  - Bellarocca by James Legg, 1997 (Box 82)
  - Manhattan Overture by James Legg, 1988 (Box 82)
  - Soft Sounds and Night Music by Joseph Leniado-Chira, 1993 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0244)
  - Relations to Rio by Scott Lindroth, undated (Box 85)
  - Eleventh Symphony by George Lloyd, 1987 (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0288)
  - Hry o Marii (The Miracles of Mary) by Bohuslav Martinu, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0044)
  - Violin Concerto by Gian Carlo Menotti, National Gallery of Art concert, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0234)
  - L'Africaine by Giacomo Meyerbeer, San Francisco Opera, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0054)
  - Air Combat Command Remembers Glenn Miller, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0052)
  - Coyote Tales by Henry Mollicone, Lyric Opera of Kansas City, 13 March 1998 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0068)
  - Opera excerpts from Starbird by Henry Mollicone and Vanessa by Samuel Barber, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0238)
  - Starbird by Henry Mollicone, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0247)
  - Starbird by Henry Mollicone, The Opera Company of North Carolina, 31 March 2001 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0045)
  - Starbird by Henry Mollicone, subtitle version, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0043)
  - The Magic Flute, Act I, by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0074)
  - The Magic Flute, Act II, Mozart, undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0075)
  - The Magic Flute, Act I, by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, Durham, North Carolina, 4 June 1988 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0076)
  - The Magic Flute, Act II, Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, Durham, North Carolina, 4 June 1988 (Box 29, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0078)
  - Signs of Life: Arioso and Scherzo by Russell Peck, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0231)
  - Upward Stream by Russell Peck, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0236)
  - Romeo and Juliet Suites by Sergei Prokofiev, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0239)
  - Sonata for Piano, Dominance and the Seduction by Keith Pruitt, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0271)
  - Piano Concerto No. 4 by Sergei Rachmaninoff, 1991 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0254)
  - "Pictures" and Other Exhibitions, Neal Ramsay, saxophone, 1989 (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0291)
  - Point of Departure, Neal Ramsay, saxophone, 1988 (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0292)
  - Fourteen Two Twenty-Two by Bruce D. Reinoso, 1990 (Box 82)
  - Memorial Concert for Akanda, with music by Bill Robinson, 2010 (Box 26, Dvd RL01344-DVD-0018)
  - South Pacific by Richard Rodgers and Oscar Hammerstein, Reel 1, undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0077)
  - The Barber of Seville by Gioachino Rossini, Florentine Opera Company, 8-9 November 1996 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0055)
  - Beat! Beat! Drums! by J. Mark Scearce, 1997 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0269)
  - XL for Orchestra by J. Mark Scearce, undated (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0284)
  - Sunday in the Park II, Stephen Sondheim, undated (Box 29, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0071)
  - Untitled, Acts I-II by Stephen Sondheim, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0233)
  - Concerto in B flat, and other works by Pamela St. John and Chuck Holton, 1991 (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0290)
  - Epiphany by Jonathan Stahlke, 1983 (Box 82)
  - America's Going to the Dickens! by Peter Stambler, 1983-1996 (Box 82)
  - The Music of Jack Stamp featuring the Keystone Winds, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0265)
  - The Music of Jack Stamp: Escapade, Symphony No. 1, Let Evening Come, 2007 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0102)
  - Tongues of Fire by William Stevens, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0067)
  - Agnus Dei by Stella Sung, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0266)
  - Bright Circles for Wind Ensemble by Stella Sung, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0262)
  - The Circle Closes by Stella Sung, 17 April 2010 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0100)
  - Constellations by Stella Sung, Orlando Philharmonic Orchestra, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0069)
  - Rockwell Reflections by Stella Sung, 1 March 2008 (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0099)
  - Conrad Susa, San Francisco Opera, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0066)
  - In an Autumn Garden by Toru Takemitsu, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0258)
  - My Way of Life by Toru Takemitsu, 15 November 1996 (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0282)
  - Fantasia on a Theme by Thomas Tallis by Ralph Vaughan Williams, undated (Box 85)
  - Falstaff by Giuseppe Verdi, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0047)
  - Falstaff by Giuseppe Verdi; Lucia di Lammermoor by Gaetano Donizetti, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0064)
  - Ballymore by Richard Wargo, three segments, Curtis Opera Theatre, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0065)
  - Ballymore by Richard Wargo, October 1996 (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0228)
  - A Chekov Trilogy, Parts 1 and 2, by Richard Wargo, August 1993 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0250)
  - A Chekov Trilogy, Part 3, by Richard Wargo, August 1993 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0251)
  - Music of Richard Wargo, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0242)
  - A Cantata of Celebrations by Donald Waxman, 2005 (Box 82)
  - Chamber pieces by Donald Waxman, undated (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0268)
  - Andante and Hungarian Rondo by Carl Maria von Weber, Westmoreland Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Kypros Markou, undated (Box 26, Cd RL01344-CD-0101)
  - Dragon Choruses by Yehudi Wyner, 1989 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0256)
  - Fragments from Antiquity by Yehudi Wyner, undated (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0280)
  - Horn Trio by Yehudi Wyner, 1997 (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0285)
  - Prologue and Narrative by Yehudi Wyner, 1994 (Box 22, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0253)
  - The Art of Conducting, 1994 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0056)
  - Assorted choral music, 1987-2006 (Box 82)
  - The Buccaneers, tape 1, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0053)
  - Carnegie Hall, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0046)
  - Creating the Dream, 31 January 1996 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0058)
  - The Festival Choir, Chiba, Japan, 1990, 1991 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0059)
  - New American Music, a sampling, 1957 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0001)
  - North Carolina Now, Dub of BC, 17 February 1994 (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0050)
  - Official Bicentennial Commemorative Album of the United Methodist Church in America, 1964 (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0287)
  - The Outstanding Contemporary Orchestral Compositions of the United States, 1974 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0011)
  - Radiant Light by Hymns and Meditations, 1998 (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0286)
  - Sing and Joyful Be, early American choral works, 1989 (Box 23, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0293)
- Untitled Recordings, 1966-2008 and undated; 8
  Contains assorted media that contain no composition titles. Recording titles are taken from the media objects themselves. Some recordings are labeled and dated as specific performances. Includes audiocassettes, compact discs, digital audio tapes, reels, and VHS tapes. Listed alphabetically by recording title; physically sorted by format.
  - Bergoms [?] Memorial Concert, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0014)
  - CD #1 Master, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0054)
  - CD #2 Master, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0055)
  - Dekalb Symphony Orchestra, 12 November 1991 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0197)
  - Durham Symphony, undated (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0002)
  - Final concerts, Kinhaven Music School, Weston, Vermont, 17-18 August 1966 (Box 30, Audio-phonodisc RL01344-PD-0022)
  - North Carolina Chamber Orchestra, 8 July 1981 (Box 29, Videotape RL01344-Umatic-0007)
  - North Carolina School of the Arts Giannini Concert, 11 November 2003 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0019)
  - Triangle Orchestra recording session, 15 May 2006 (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0026)
  - PCM 3700, III, 16 April 1991 (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0023)
  - PT 109, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0001)
  - Recording session at Reynolds Theater, Duke University, 17 August 1998 (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0031)
  - Safety recording, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0026)
  - Takes 33-67, 19 December 1991 (Box 19, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0155)
  - The Triangle Youth Philharmonic, 23 November 1997 (Box 27, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0001)
  - Robert Ward Compilation CD, Vochor Digital Recording, edited evaluation CD, 2008 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0057)
  - Robert Ward compilation CD version 2, re-edited gaps, 22 July 2008 (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0059)
  - Robert Ward Concert, University of Wisconsin, 24 September 1990 (Box 20, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0194)
  - Robert Ward, Digital, undated (Box 30, Audio-reel RL01344-DRR-0001)
  - Robert Ward edit, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0030)
  - Robert Ward Songs, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0024)
  - Robert Ward Takes 1-43, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0006)
  - Robert Ward Takes 44-72, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0007)
  - Robert Ward Takes 73-103, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0008)
  - Robert Ward Takes 104-170, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0009)
  - Robert Ward Takes 171-186, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0010)
  - Robert Ward recording session, sides 1-2, 17 August 1998 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0017)
  - Robert Ward recording session, side 3, 17 August 1998 (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0018)
  - Robert Ward takes 43-72, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0020)
  - Robert Ward takes 73-103, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0021)
  - Robert Ward takes 104-, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0022)
  - Robert Ward takes 171-186, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0023)
  - Robert Ward takes -171, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0024)
  - Ward Recording at 3700 Duke, Studio I, 15 April 1991 (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0021)
  - Ward Recording at 3700 Duke, Studio II, 15 April 1991 (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0022)
  - Ward CD Eval, No level changes, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0031)
  - Ward Opera Demo #1, undated (Box 24, Cd RL01344-CD-0036)
  - Ward CD #2, undated (Box 25, Cd RL01344-CD-0049)
  - Ward, Ross, Johnson, Rendleman, undated (Box 21, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0226)
  - Music of Robert Ward, North Carolina Symphony, undated (Box 15, Audio-cassette RL01344-CS-0028)
  - Unknown performers, undated (Box 29, Videotape RL01344-Umatic-0008)
  - Unknown content, undated (Box 14, Digital-audio-tape RL01344-DAT-0028)
  - Unknown performers, undated (Box 31, Audio-reel RL01344-RR-0031)
  - Untitled recording, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0060)
  - Untitled recording, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0061)
  - Untitled recording, undated (Box 28, Video-cassette RL01344-VHS-0062)